Guide to the Stanford University, Summer Festival of the Arts, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Summer Festival of the Arts, records
1964-1969
SC0074
Stanford University. Summer Festival of the Arts.
10.5 Linear feet
Correspondence, notes, budget statements, memos, planning reports arranged by festival year, photographs of rehearsals, performances and publicity shots, posters, and scrapbooks containing newsclippings of the Summer Festival programs.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, Stanford Summer Festival, 1970; and gift of the estate of Steven Baffrey, 1996.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, notes, budget statements, memos, planning reports arranged by festival year, photographs of rehearsals, performances and publicity shots, posters, and scrapbooks containing newsclippings of the Summer Festival programs.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Summer Festival of the Arts.; Performing arts festivals--California.; Photoprints.; Scrapbooks; Student activities.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Committee, reports, notes, memos, 1964-66 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Budgets, Correspondence and reports, 1964- 67 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A proposal for a Summer Festival at Stanford, 1962 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Candidates for Positions, Correspondence, note s and memos, 1964-66 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - notes, correspondence, memos, programs., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - V. K. Wtbtaker's European trip; Booklets and programs from various Festivals in many parts of Europe., 1964-65 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - correspondence, notes, memos, magnetic tape of Audience briefing, August 9, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - notes, memos, correspondence, 1966 January - June (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - notes, memos, correspondence, 1966 July -August (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - notes, memos, correspondence, 1966 Sep- Dec (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Future years, correspondence, 1965- 68 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1967, correspondence, notes, memos re: 1967 Festival, Augus t - De cember, 1966, January October, 1967. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1968, correspondence, December, 1965 -July, 1968 re: 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1969, Correspondence, March 31, 1967-March 14, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Programs, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Programs, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Programs, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Programs, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Shakespeare: Newspaper clipping, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Shakespeare photographs, 1964 (Box 5)
    Includes:
    a) Shakespeare: rehearsals and performances.
    b) Shakespeare: sets and general promotional pictures.
    c) Shakespeare: miscellaneous publicity shots.
    d) Shakespeare: miscellaneous shots, possibly inclucding the Duchess of Malfi
  - The Mozart Era, Newspaper clippings concerning the Festival, 1965 (Box 6)
  - The Mozart Era,. Photographs and programs, 1965 June 22-August 14 (Box 7)
  - 20th Century Innovations: photographs of participating artists and pe rformers., 1966 (Box 8)
  - 20th Century Innovations: newspaper clippings re: Festival and programs, 1966 (Box 9)
  - Focus on America: photographs of performances, 1967 (Box 10)
  - Focus on America: newspaper clippings concerning the Festival, 1967 (Box 11)
  - Fifth Anniversary Season, newspaper clippings, 1968 June 25-August 11 (Box 12)
  - Sixth Annual Season, newspaper clippings, 1969 June 24-August 17 (Box 13)
- Records, Accession ARCH-1996-172
  - Scrapbook of photographs, clippings, and programs of the 1964 season, Shakespeare (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook of photographs, clippings, and programs of the 1965 season, the Mozart era (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook of clippings and programs of the 1966 season, 20th century variations (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook of clippings and programs of the 1967 season, Focus on America (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook of clippings and programs of the 1968 season (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook of clippings and programs of the 1969 season (Box 2)
  - Framed items:
    - Photograph of lights being set at Frost Amphitheater
    - Photograph of a scene from a play
    - Original art for the 1966 program
  - Rolled items:
    - Posters, 1960s